CV / Wojciech Olejnik - Senior Software Engineer

I'm a full-stack software engineer with 7 years of professional experience in building Web and Mobile applications as well as REST APIs and other backend services. I specialize in React on the front-end side and Ruby on Rails/Node.js on the back-end, but can work effectively in almost any technology stack. During my career in consulting I've worked with international teams on projects from a variety of industries including education, automotive, fintech, music streaming, e-commerce, tourism and agriculture. I enjoy working on innovative and meaningful projects and value software that's performant and has great user experience.

SKILLS

```
TypeScript/JavaScript \mid CSS/Sass \mid Node.js \mid Ruby \mid Rust \mid Python \mid C/C++ \mid SQL \mid HTML5 \& browser APIs \mid React \mid React Native \mid Redux/Pullstate \mid Electron \mid RWD \mid Figma \mid Ruby on Rails \mid Express.js \mid CI/CD \mid Git \mid MongoDB \mid PostgreSQL \mid Redis \mid Linux \mid Agile \mid TDD \mid Bots/Automation \mid Docker \mid Kubernetes \mid Amazon AWS \mid Unity \mid
```

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

BCF Software Sp. z o.o. - Senior C++ Developer

JUNE 2022 - AUGUST 2022

• Outsourced to Nokia to help develop their distributed software for 5G Mobile Networks, using C++, ZeroMQ, ASN.1, Protobuf and TTCN-3 among other things.

STF Sulama Sistemleri — Freelance Software Developer

APRIL 2021 - JULY 2022

- The project involved a mobile companion app for the company's hardware products IoT devices for the Turkish agriculture industry.
- I developed the iOS and Android applications in React Native (using TypeScript) with the help of libraries such as React Query, Redux and Reanimated.
- I also designed and built a JSON REST API for the mobile app using *Ruby on Rails*, *Grape*, *Sidekiq*, *PostgreSQL* and *Redis*.

Netguru S.A - Senior Full-stack Web Developer

MAY 2018 - APRIL 2021

- Built an innovative chat-like booking system for service appointments at car dealerships, deployed as an embeddable widget, web application and a mobile application running in a kiosk device. Implemented as SPAs in *React* & *Redux* with a *WebSocket*-based back-end.
- Spent a year working as an R&D Tech Lead, coordinating the work of dozens of rotating developers, maintaining the company's Software Radar, leading the development of internal projects and experimenting with emerging technologies

such as WASM, Serverless, WebSockets and Blockchain. During this time I've had a chance to work with a variety of languages and tools including Node.js, Rust, C++, Python, Vue.js, GraphQL, ASP.NET, React Native, AWS Lambda and Google Cloud Functions.

- Took a crucial part in the design process and then implemented a promotional coupons marketplace for an enterprise benefits provider (Sodexo). Stack included *React*, *React Admin*, *Next.js*, *Ruby on Rails*, *PostgreSQL* and *Redis*.
- Helped build a part of the mobile app of Poland's largest convenience store chain (Żabka).

Netguru S.A - Full-stack Web Developer

OCTOBER 2015 - MAY 2018

- Developed a sales support system for car dealerships including features like SMS messaging and calls (using Twilio). Built with React embedded in a Ruby on Rails application for server-side rendering.
- Worked on an established hotel management system, where my task was to ensure the responsiveness of the user-facing UI.
- Built an investment platform for a FinTech startup with a **JSON API** aggregating large amounts of data from a 3rd party provider and a front-end UI developed in **Ember.js**.
- Worked on a non-profit IT education platform for young students built with *Ruby on Rails*, *Alchemy CMS* and *jQuery*.
- Maintained a legacy codebase of a music streaming platform built with Sinatra, MongoDB, Resque, Elasticsearch and Backbone.js. Also built a standalone music player for this website in the form of a browser extension, using React and Redux.

EDUCATION

Adam Mickiewicz University, Poznań

OCTOBER 2013 - FEBRUARY 2017

Engineer's Degree in Computer Science

• Specialization: Mobile Technologies

SPOKEN LANGUAGES

- Polish native
- English advanced (CEFR-level C1)

ACHIEVEMENTS

 Won 1st place at Microsoft Imagine Cup's Eastern European finals in the "Innovation" category with my project "MIDI Studio VR" (2017)

PERSONAL INTERESTS

Low-level programming, Electrical engineering, Space exploration, Game development, Motorcycles, 3D printing